Hi, in a previous video
嗨，在之前的视频里
I told you about two scenarios in which a VLOOKUP function is not the
我告诉过你在两种情况下 VLOOKUP函数不是
perfect solution.
完美的解决方案。
First, if you need speed, and second, if you want to have lookups
第一，如果你需要的是速​​度，和第二， 如果你想要查找
that go back stream, the strange direction for a VLOOKUP.
返流，这对于VLOOKUP函数来说是个奇怪的方向。
So, in this video I'm going to show you
所以，在这个视频，我要告诉你
how to resolve that situation, where I am going to teach you two new methods
如何解决这种情况，我将教你两种新方法
to solve it. But first let's take a step back, let's take our time machine
来解決这个问题。 但首先，让我们退一步，用时光机器
and go back to the second video in which I talked about what the exact
回到第二个视频中， 我谈到了
ingredients are
lookup函数
for a lookup function. It was: what am I going to look for,
的要素。 就是：我要寻找什么，
where am I looking it up, and what am I going to return.
我寻找的范围是什么，我要取回什么。
Those three ingredients occur
这是VLOOKUP函数里
in VLOOKUP function. For our new implementation using two new functions
的三个要素。 现在我们要使用两个新函数
we're going to split those two parts, so we use one function
我们要分开这两个部分，所以 我们用一个函数
for finding a value and one function for returning a value.
查找值，一个函数 返回一个值。
And for finding a value we're going to use the
对于查找值，我们要使用
MATCH function, and here, in this video I'll show you how it works.
MATCH函数，在这个视频里，我会告诉你它如何工作。
So we type in 'MATCH', we use the MATCH function,
我们输入“MATCH”，我们使用MATCH 函数，
we input what are we going to look for, and the second parameter
我们输入我们需要查找的内容， 第二个参数
is where am I going to find it. The third parameter is very similar to the fourth
代表我会在哪里查找它。 第三个参数非常相似于
parameter of the VLOOKUP, where I can say
VLOOKUP函数里的第四个参数，可以说
I want to have a value that's higher, exact value,
我想有一个更高精度的值
or lower. And we pick the exact value here, much like
或更低的值。 在这我们选了精确值， 很像
the FALSE option in VLOOKUP. So you see
VLOOKUP的FALSE选项。 所以 你看
Claw Hammer, A0, is on the second line. It's not that impressive so let me sort
木工锤，A0，是在第二行。 这不是很直观，所以让我
the ProductInfo worksheet so then you can see exactly how the MATCH works. So we've
在ProductInfo 工作表上排序，这样就可以看到MATCH是怎么工作的。 所以我们现在将它排序
A0 is now in the sixth line and our MATCH function
A0在第六行，我们的 MATCH函数
indeed returns A0 code is on
的确返回了A0代码，就在
row 6. That's what the MATCH
第6行。 这就是Match函数的
function does - for a given range it tells you on what
功能 - 在一个给定的范围内它告诉你
row a given value is. So we have the first part of our
一个给定值是在哪一行上。 因此，我们就完成了我们新使用场景
new scenario covered. What about the second part? For the second part we're
第一个部分 那第二部分又是什么呢？ 关于第二部分
going to use the
我们将要使用的
INDEX function.
INDEX函数。
INDEX function is going to return us in a given range
INDEX函数将回传给定的行与列范围
this specific row and column. So here you can see how it looks.
的数据给我们。 所以在这里你可以看看它的形式。
Again, we know that A0 is on the sixth row,
同样，我们知道，A0是在 第六列中，
but we want to have the name instead of the code.
但我们希望要的是名称而不是 的代码。
So, we go back to our original formula, we remove the MATCH, we just put it with
因此，我们回到我们原来的公式， 我们删除了MATCH函数，我们使用了
"Ctrl X" on the clipboard. We put in the INDEX.
“CTRL X”把它放到剪切板上。 我们放入 INDEX函数。
What are we going to return? We are going to return the B column.
我们要返回什么呢？ 我们要返回B列。
That's the first parameter, what are we going to return, what
这是第一个参数，我们要返回的内容，哪一
row. Well we know the row. The row where we have just
行。 嗯，我们知道哪一行。 我们刚刚
found our value. And what column? Well, B is only one column
查找到数值的那一行。 哪一列？ B是唯一的那一列
so we're just inputting 1 there. So now you see we have the name
所以我们只要在那输入1。 所以，现在你发现我们在刚配对的地方让名称与
associated with the value, the line number,
值产生关联，
on which we have just matched. And, as you can see,
而且，正如你所看到，
you see me double-click and run this INDEX-MATCH
你看道我双击并在上千的行数上
function for the entire, all thousands of lines.
运行此 INDEX-MATCH函数。
You see the first benefit - speed! It's really a lot quicker.
你看到的第一个好处 - 速度！ 真的快了很多。
But using INDEX-MATCH
但使用INDEX-MATCH
over the VLOOKUP has another benefit. You remember this scenario
代替VLOOKUP还有一个好处。 你还记得在这种场景中，
where our boss comes in and says "Hey, I want to have
我们的老板进来说：“嘿，我 希望
these codes associated with these products, because I want to enter
这些代码与产品能互相关联，
them
因为我想将他们
in the register, because I want to enter a discount".
输入到收银机，因为我想键入折扣数据“。
We can solve this problem now. We tried with a VLOOKUP with the -1.
我们现在可以解决这个问题。 我们用VLOOKUP，鍵入-1。
Let's get rid of that and let's use an INDEX-MATCH here as well.
让我们把这这删除掉，在这里我们使用INDEX-MATCH。
I like to start with the MATCH part because it's easier to debug,
我想先从MATCH部分开始因为它更容易除错，
it's easier to see what is being matched if it doesn't work.
它更容易看到，如果匹配 是行不通的，结果会如何。
So let's match. We're going to look for the Name in the B column
因此，让我们开始匹配。 我们要去寻找在B栏中的Name
and return the exact match - there it is!
并回传相同匹配数据-就在那！
We know this by now, the Claw Hammer is on the sixth line. So we remove the MATCH,
我们知道这现在木工锤是 在第六行。 所以，我们删除了MATCH，
we just cut it for a while, now we input the INDEX.
我们只是暂时删除，现在我们键入 INDEX。
What are we going to return? Codes!
我们要回传什么呢？ Codes！
What row do we want to return? Well, we know this, we could have entered 6, because
我们想要返回哪一行？ 嗯，我们都知道 可以输入6，
we know the line,
因为我们知道那一行，
but we enter the MATCH function there, and it's only one column,
但我们可以在MATCH函数那里输入， 它只有一列，
so we use 1. So you see the second benefit
然后我们用1。 所以你就看到INDEX-MATCH比VLOOKUP好的
of using INDEX-MATCH over VLOOKUP is
的第二点
going back-stream.
返回流。
It doesn't matter what we want to return, in this case you want to return our
它和我们要返回的内容无关， 在这种情况下，你想返回
next-door neighbour, but we can do anything! The INDEX-MATCH is very flexible,
隔壁的值，然而我们可以返回任何值！ INDEX-MATCH是非常灵活的，
we could also return, if we have match here, return
我们还可以返回，如果我们在这有匹配函数，那么返回
the cell below it, or the sell three to the right and one
它下面的单元格，或减去三加到右边，还是加在
on top, it doesn't matter! The INDEX-MATCH
上面，都没有关系！ INDEX-MATCH
lets you return anything you want. So for some scenarios
可以返回你想要的任何东西。 因此，在某些方案中
INDEX-MATCH is better than VLOOKUP. See you next week!
INDEX-MATCH比VLOOKUP更好。 我们下周见！